英文翻译：Sharon    字幕制作：cocok7
圣诞特辑
每年我都得跟皮克维尔小姐解释
Every year I'd explain to Miss Pickwell
圣诞节就是耶稣基督的诞辰
that the Nativity is about Jesus being born,
而不是他被鞭打 钉十字架的那天
not him being beaten, whipped and crucified in real time.
没错 她对犹太人被屠杀也表现出了那么点忧桑
Yeah, she also went a little bit heavy with the Jew-bashing.
格林教授是代替她的确定人选 不过她...
Pro Green was a shoe-in to replace her, but she's, er....
在和我爸度蜜月 是的 我再清楚不过了
On honeymoon with my dad,yes, I know.
我一直想忘记那个
I'm trying not to think about it.
我的观点就是 除非你亲自出马 不然就没有圣诞剧表演了
My point is, there'll be no Xmas play unless you step up to the plate.
好吧 弗瑞泽 我马上就跟你说我为啥不想上场
OK, Fraser, I'll tell you why I'm not going to do the play.
我以前也不是这样...
I was like everyone else...
在我小时候 圣诞剧演出是圣诞节的高潮部分
when I was growing up, Nativities were the highlight of my Christmas.
之后 有一年 我演了一个最棒的角色
And then, one year,I got the best part I'd ever got.
约瑟?
Joseph?
二号小鼹鼠
Mole 2.
马槽里有鼹鼠吗?这个嘛 应该有的
Were there moles in the manger?Er, yes.
我是妈妈答应我 她会来看我的演出...
My mum promised that she'd come and watch me...
到我出场的时候 你知道我看到了什么吗?
And I went out on stage,do you know what I saw?
什么都没看到?鼹鼠都是瞎的 才不是...
Nothing? Moles are blind. No...
我妈妈的座位是空的
My mum's empty chair.
于是那只可怜的小鼹鼠就只想挖个洞钻到地底下 然后消失
And that poor little mole just wanted to burrow down into the ground and disappear.
不过 你看哈 你不需要做耶稣诞生表演!
But look,you don't have to do a Nativity!
我们搞一个跨教派表演就行
It's time for a non-denominational show.
替"所有的宗教"大声叫好么!
Give a shout out to "all de religion"!
你可别忘了
Hey, but don't forget mine.
我可是信比伯的!
I'm a Belieber!
是啊 那我就是亵渎比伯之徒
Yeah, well I'm a Bl-atheist.
不过 从学术上说 我是比伯盲
Actually, technically,I think I'd be Bl-agnostic.
就是说 我会骂死他
I mean, I'd slag him off
现在他要是能从门外走进来 我就像狗皮膏药似的粘着他
but if he walked in the door now,I'd be all over him like a rash.
哈!诡计多端的圣诞老人刚刚从他的袋子里掏出了一份大礼呢
Woo-hoo! Banter Claus just pulled a big one from his gag sack.
你还是杀了我算了 我说 你得让史蒂芬参加才行
Kill me. Hey,you've got to get Stephen involved!
那货可有表演天赋了
That guy knows how to put on a show.
记不记得他的个人秀《珍爱人生》么?
Remember his one-man Precious?
棒极了!
Superb!
《浪人荒原》?
Fiddler on the Heath?
《巡回风暴》
Barnstorming.
还有《雪莉·柯尔传》...
And that biopic of Cheryl Cole...
这个有损形象
Libellous.
不管怎么说 我想问 你还记得你用短信发学期末报告这事儿吗?
Anyhoo, question, remember how you sent your end-of-term reports via text?
当然 那可是我最有创意的主意之一
Yeah, one of my best ideas ever.
是嘛 我看校领导好像不这么觉得呢
Yeah, well, the school governors don't seem to think so.
你这家伙!
Dicks!
他们可是一直想让我炒你鱿鱼呢
They're quite keen for me to fire you.
不过要是你肯出演这部圣诞剧
But you put on this play,
我就保你没事
and I'll save your heiney
让领导们有事都冲我来 护你到底
by throwing this ass in front of the governors' spanking hands.
成交 我就去演一下你那个破剧
All right.I'll do your shitty little play.
不过 还是得告诉你 我讨厌圣诞演出
But, just so you know,I hate Christmas shows.
提前准备的好东西
We have done some perfectly good stuff earlier in the year,
现在都派不上用场了 本来节日就够乱了 还得赶着重弄
and now we have to ruin it by cobbling together some under-thought through festive bollocks
用一坨坨见鬼的圣诞曲子
with a load of shit Christmas music.
谁给我的西汉姆联队赛的门票?
Who got me a ticket to West Ham?
我誓死支持米尔沃队
I'm Millwall till I die.
投票结果如下 《胡桃夹子》六票 《机器战警》五票
OK, so six of you have voted for The Nutcracker and five of you have voted for Robocop.
所以我们要演《胡桃夹子》吗?
So we're doing the Nutcracker?
有人不坚持民主原则了吗?
Oh, someone's changed their tune on democracy.
你别忘了 静 还有我的一票呢
But you're forgetting, Jing,I also get a vote.
所以我们到底要演什么?
So what are we going to do?
有了
Got it.
我们就演这个了
That's our play.
《机器小钳子》?
Robocracker?
有这种东西吗? 现在还没有 只是现在而已
Does that exist?Not yet, my friend. Not yet.
神呢 你所谓的剧本是什么 大家再了解不过了
Oh, God,we've read your scripts before.
干嘛这副反应?你也不知道细节 不是吗?
What do you mean, "Oh, God"? You don't really do subtlety, do you?
好吧 细节问题会让我发疯的
Er, subtlety can lick my balls and then eat a plate of my ass for dessert.
我得去维基百科查查 决定情节的混搭问题
I'll just go on Wikipedia,bosh out a plot mash-up.
没用的 不 肯定有用
That's not going to work.Er, yes, it will.
最近20年最好的电影的哪部?
What's the best film of the last 20 years?
《电锯惊魂4》《电锯惊魂5》
Saw 4. Saw 5.
《饥饿游戏》《拜见岳父大人》《洛丽塔》
Hunger Games. Meet the Fockers.Lolita.
《尖峰时刻》也不错的 静
Hmm, Rush Hour's a good shout, Jing,
不过正确的答案是《异形战场》
but the correct answer is Alien Vs Predator.
情节的混搭
A plot mash-up.
伙计 要是我爸知道我登台表演 他一定会想方设法掐灭我这点儿念头
Mate, if my dad finds out I've been on stage, he'll cut me out the will.
也就是说你不用继承他那套破破烂烂的运动服了吗?
So you won't have to inherit his shitty tracksuits?
我觉得也是!你也你得不到你妈的衣服 那些可都躺在我的卧室的地板上呢!
That makes two of us! You won't be getting your mum's clothes, cos they're all over my bedroom floor!
同学们 积点口德 不要问候对方的长辈
Guys, stop being mean about each other's families.
你们的爹妈一直给予你们支持和帮助
Your parents are all so supportive of you.
可能你们现在还没什么感觉
You might not realise it now,
但是 你永远不会明白他们有多爱你 直到你的母亲离开...
but you won't appreciate how much they love you, until your mum's gone...
..去西班牙定居 和哈维尔以及他们的孩子生活在一起
..to live in Spain,with Javier and their children.
哎呦!
Gay!
加油 老师
Come on, sir.
你来写剧本 我帮你安排他们试镜
You write your masterpiece,I'll help you organise auditions.
谢了 静
Thanks, Jing.
我还忘了说 我们得为所有的教派大声叫好
Oh, and I forgot to say, we have to give a shout out to all the religions.
基督教 佛教 伊斯兰教...中国有什么教 静?
Christianity, Buddhism, Islam...what's China, Jing?
大多数人不信教的 所以你们不过圣诞节吗?
Predominantly atheists. So, what,you don't get to do Christmas?
有点不公平哎 毕竟玩具都是中国制造
That seems a bit unfair considering you make all the toys.
就好比 圣诞精灵没有圣诞礼物
That's like the elves not having it.
你刚刚是在比较...?
Did you just compare...?
说到圣诞礼物 米契尔 格老师的礼物准备好了么?
On the subject of presents,Mitchell, how is Miss Gulliver's?
嗯 我爸特地挑选的 他一哥们儿开了个野驴收容所
Yeah. Dad's sorted it. One of his mates owns a donkey sanctuary.
你给格老师买了一头驴?让她收养一头驴
You're buying Miss Gulliver a donkey? Adopting her a donkey.
你懂的 她喜欢动物...而且 驴比雪豹便宜多了
You know, she loves animals... and they're a lot cheaper than snow leopards.
好了 再强调一次
OK, spread the word.
预选要开始了 都去找找试镜灵感 好好准备喔
Casting's at break, so pick your own audition pieces and choose them wisely.
史蒂芬 今天你准备《霹雳舞》里的那场戏呢?
OK, Stephen, what scene from Flashdance are you doing today?
全部 全部?
All of it. All of it?
你只有一分钟喔 闭嘴看我表演就行
You've only got a minute.Just shut up and press play.
你是谁呢?
And who are you?
泽维尔教授 X战警 是不是?
Professor Xavier. X-Men, innit?
我会读心术 哥们儿
I can read your mind, bruv.
是啊 哈
Yeah, sure.
我在想什么?
What am I thinking now?
乳头
Tits.
乳头!
Tits!
他是怎么做到的?
How does he do it?
仙黛尔 你的灵感来自哪里?
So, Chantelle, where have you taken your scene from?
本能
Basic Instinct.
本能...?
Basic Instinct...?
我凑!别动!
Oh, my God! Do not move your legs!
很明显 你还沉浸在自己的剧里呢 真是难以置信
Obviously, you're in the play.That was amazing.
就他了
Sorted.
我们还是有一名好演员的
We still only have one good actor.
是啊 你就看着那个好点
Yeah, that's all you need.One good one,
然后就不知道其他的多惨不忍睹
then you don't realise how terrible the other ones actually are.
就跟卡戴珊似的 是吗?没错 当三联画正好
It's like the Kardashians. Really?Yeah, as a triptych, fit.
不过把金排除在外
But you take Kim out of the equation,
考特尼似乎应该坐在桥底下 守着桥啃山羊
Kourtney suddenly looks like she should be sat underneath a bridge that she guards, eating goats.
现在 弗兰克 没必要这么严肃...
Now, look, Frank,there's no need to take the piss...
我来试镜了 不是么?
I've come to audition, innit?
你的舞蹈 半好半坏吧
Your dance was, like, good and shit.
真谢谢你啊 亲
Oh, thanks, babes.
不管怎么说 我没事的
Oh, whatever, man. I'm not bothered.
那么 好吧... 该你表演了
Well, OK, um... in your own time.
这个表演可能会很精彩呢 静
This is going to be perfect, Jing.
他会是我们的B计划 虽然喜怒无常 但是个表演天才
He'll be like Plan B, all moody but with an amazing talent
大隐于市 偶尔会露面
hidden between the urban, slightly stabby facade.
我的罗密欧呢?
Where is my Romeo?
这是什么?一只杯子 紧紧地握住在我的忠心的爱人的手里?
What's here?A cup, closed in my love's true hand?
我知道了 一定是毒药结果了他的生命
Poison, I see,hath been his timeless end.
他好像在大便似的
He sounds like he's taking a shit.
我要吻着你的嘴唇...
I will kiss thy lips...
很好 就到这儿吧
OK, right, good.
嗯...所以 也有演得不错的地方
Er...so, let's start with the positives.
音量
Volume.
声音非常洪亮啊
It was very loud.
我每个词都听得清清楚楚 我确实在想 整个赫特福德郡
I heard every word, as I think did the whole of Hertfordshire.
所以我要演什么角色?
So what part am I going to play?
很遗憾地说 弗兰克 我们已经有足够多的优秀的演员了
Er, unfortunately, Frank, there are a lot of really great actors out there.
什么角色?很遗憾地说 你落选...
What part? I'm afraid,there isn't a role for you...
什么...角色?
What... part?
主演?什么?联袂主演
The lead? What? The co-lead.
没错 就跟在《尖峰时刻》里那样
Yes, like in Rush Hour.
谢了 静
Thanks, Jing.
救得好
Nice save.
你还好么 老师?
You all right, sir?
不错啊 你呢?
I'm snow-K, you?
我也还好
Yeah, not too bad.
你自己呢?
Yours-elf?
鲁道夫等圣诞老人的鹿!
Oh, Rudolph, Donner,Blitzen and Banter!
能把威克斯老师母亲的电话给我吗?
Can I get Mr Wickers' mum's number,please, sir?
在厕所的墙上写着呢 我试过那个了 打不通
It's on the toilet wall. Yeah,I tried that one. It weren't real.
抱歉 你为啥想要那个呢?我给威克斯老师准备了一个惊喜
Sorry, why do you want it?I'm arranging Mr Wickers a nice surprise.
真的是惊喜?毕竟是圣诞节嘛
Genuinely nice? Yeah.It's Christmas.
我想让您邀请她去看威克斯老师的表演 哦!
I want to invite her to Mr Wickers' play. Wow!
你知道吗 不管是糖衣炮弹还是什么 我都同意
Do you know what, hustler, I think I'm going to drop that goodwill pill you just scored me.
虽然艾尔非不见他妈妈好多年
Although Alfie's not seen her in years.
你必须相信他 做点准备 好的
Well, you've got to convince her then. Make something up. Right-oh.
您好 请问是威克斯夫人吗?
Hello, is that Mrs Wickers?
抱歉 现在应该称呼您加西亚·拉米雷斯夫人!
Sorry, currently Mrs Garcia-Ramires!
没错 我是弗瑞泽
Yes, it's Mr Fraser here.
艾尔非他...
Alfie's...
..出车祸了 非常严重
..been in a horrific car crash.
所以这就是机器小钳子
OK, so this is Robocracker.
在一个毫无希望的世界 住着一个有情绪问题的不良少年
In a world without hope, lived an angry maladjusted delinquent boy.
就是你 弗兰克
That is you, Frank.
在圣诞清晨 弗兰克醒来 发现圣诞树下有个玩偶 是机器小钳子
Frank wakes up Christmas morning, finds beneath the tree a doll, it's Robocracker.
就是你 史蒂芬
That's you, Stephen.
圣诞节发生的奇迹 小钳子活了!
Christmas miracle,Robocracker's alive!
而且 他和这个问题男孩一起 开始了维护世界和平的正义之旅
And him and the delinquent boy set about to bring peace to the world.
轰动英国 一夜爆红 嗅到电影学院奖的气息了吗?
Sprinkle in a couple of explosions, throw in a sex scene, bish bash bosh, who smells BAFTA?
光靠这部剧 你可赢不了英国电影学院奖
You can't win a BAFTA for a theatre show.
所有的角色都有人了 不过谁来演反派角色...
All the parts are cast, except for the role of the villain...
朝鲜的暴君 金正恩
North Korean despot, Kim Jong-un.
谁 谁来演这个角色呢?
Oh, who, oh, who could play that part?
你想让我演一个大腹便便的 中年朝鲜老男人?
You want me to play an overweight middle-aged North Korean man?
别误会 静 那是他以前的形象 现在我们不提那个
Er, no, Jing, we're not talking about a lazy stereotype here.
我们要塑造的是一个有血有肉 形象丰满的人物角色
We are talking about a three-dimensional, very rounded character,
一个胖乎乎的 特立独行的孤独者...
a very rounded sort of, chubby oddball loner...
赶快给我剧本
Just give me the script.
乔 你要演金正恩吗 一个闪闪发光 更为亲和的金正恩
Joe, you are going to make a brilliant not-so-Lil' Kim.
金正恩为啥会出现在《机器小钳子》里?
How is Kim Jong-un in Robocracker?
因为金正恩想抓机器人小钳子
Because Kim Jong-un wants to capture Robocracker
得到小钳子的心脏 制造一种导弹 他就可以摧毁世界了
so he can use his robotic heart to power a missile that can destroy the world.
只有得到了那颗心脏 他才知道心脏并不是机械的
Only when he gets hold of the heart,he realises it's not robotic,
那是一颗正常的 人类男孩的心脏
it's actually the heart of a real boy.
这再明显不过了 想想就明白了 静
It's actually very obvious if you think about it, Jing.
谢了 老师 好凄美的故事啊
Thank you, sir, it's beautiful.
为什么不干脆做莎士比亚剧呢?
Why can't we just do Shakespeare?
同样的理由 我也不看《质询时间》
For the same reason that I don't watch Question Time.
又无聊 也看不懂 观众还时不时就爆笑
Because it's boring, confusing and the audience laugh at a load of jokes
因为一卡车没几个正常人会懂的笑话
that no normal person would ever understand.
所以如何来营造一种忠诚 信任又幸福的氛围呢?
So, how do we create a loyal, trusting, happy environment?
大家都裸体吗?
Everyone get naked?
毫无
No.
只要躺在地板上 让别人从你身上滚过去就行
What we do is we all lie on the floor,and then take turns to roll over each other.
选一个搭档
Pick a partner.
我选乔
I'll take Joe.
做好准备 开始滚就行了
When you're ready, just over you go.
马上过去了 好家伙...
Nearly there, big guy...
我的老腰!
Oh, my back!
啊!
Argh!
等一下
Rem Dogg!
老师到我了吗?不 不要...
Is it my go, sir? No, no...
相信我啊 老师!
Trust me, sir!
你要滚去哪?
Where are you going?
相信我!
Trust me!
你好啊
Hello.
那个 我们在做一个信任实践的排演
Er,we were just doing a trust exercise.
好吧
Right.
我想知道 今晚的圣诞特别节目 谁要加入呢?
Er, I was wondering who's coming on our special outing this evening?
凑!抱歉 我把这事给忘了!
Oh, shit! Sorry. I forgot to ask!
同学们 谁想跟格老师一起去呢...
Er, guys, do any of you want to go with Miss Gulliver...
还有威克斯老师 没错 还有我...
And Mr Wickers. And me...
去一个可爱的 收留流浪汉的施粥场
to a lovely, trampy soup kitchen?
我可不想手淫
I'm not going tramp-wanking.
没有手淫的 米切尔
Er, there's no wanking involved,Mitchell.
有么?
Is there?
我们为什么要对流浪汉手淫呢?
Why would we wank off tramps?
为他们取暖么?
To keep them warm?
有人愿意去吗?
Does anyone want to volunteer?
罗西啊 事实就是 我们在搞一个这样的剧
The thing is, Rosie,er, we're kind of doing this play,
没有太多的时间去干那个
so we don't really have much spare time.
而且 我不会说苏格兰语 所以我和那些流浪汉没法儿...
Plus, I don't speak Scottish,so me and tramps don't really...
艾尔非 你最好不要后悔
Alfie, I am going to make you stick to your promise.
很抱歉 我非弄这个剧不可
Well, I'm sorry,I have to do this play.
领导发话我才去
I need to get the governors back on board.
恐怕这次我是怎么都不会去了
So I'm afraid on this occasion I am putting my foot down.
不好玩么?
Isn't this fun?
我把你弄这儿来 你不高兴吗?
Aren't you glad I made you come?
是啊!
Yeah!
给我些巴奇 兄弟!
Gie us some Bucky, pal!
巴奇?是种酒
Bucky? It's alcohol.
是这样的 你看 在施粥场我们只提供粥
Yeah, look, I'm afraid we only serve soup in this soup kitchen.
去你妈的 你个混蛋
Get tae fuck, ya sleekit wee bastard,
给我们点巴奇 不然你死哪儿都不知道 有钱的混球!
gie us some Bucky or ye'll end up in a ditch, you toff buftie!
额 这是苏格兰语的"给我些巴豆"的意思么?
OK, is that Scottish for,"Yes, please, with croutons"?
别告诉我该干吗
Oi, dinnae you be tellin' me whit tae dae!
我才是老大
You're nae the boss o' me,ya doss radge dug.
好可爱的狗狗啊!
Ah, what a lovely doggie!
它叫什么?
What's his name?
这个...
Er...
"要是您找到我们的狗 请拨打020..."丫的 是数字
"If found, please call 020..."Och, numbers.
一条狗叫这种名 怪死了
What an odd name to give a dog.
不 不  这可不是我的狗
No, no, he's no' mine.
我从一笨蛋那偷来的 他在街上把我揍了一顿
I stole him aff some numpty-heided bastard who tried tae gie me a doin' in the street.
太惨了
How awful.
是啊 那货拿着根这种棍子朝我们走过来  不过我们把他甩掉了
Aye, he came at us wi' a stick!Eh, eh! But I got it off him.
谁愿意和瘦骨头干架呢
Cos nae-one messes wi' Boney.
你们谁要我就卖给你们
I'll sell it tae youse if ye like,yeah, no?
还有这个
Got these an' all.
全新的喔
Brand-new, like.
老师!
Sir!
流浪汉们不可爱吗?
Aren't tramps lovely?
老师 你想要雄驴还是雌驴?
Sir, what sort of donkey do you want,a boy or a girl?
最可爱的就行
Just whatever looks cutest.
但是 小钳子 若是不能随音乐起舞 我们如何消灭艾滋呢?
But, Robocracker, how can we cure AIDS with no music to dance to?
不必担心 弗兰克 我碰巧是波诺最好的朋友!
Never fear, Frank, because I happen to be best friends with Bono!
然后你要拥抱他
And then you hug him.
我不抱男人
I'm not hugging any blokes.
小伙子们 我能提点建议么?
Lads, can I gie ye a wee bit of advice?
把你自己想象成一块空白的画布 把你对角色的理解描摹于上
Think of yourselves as blank canvases on to which your characters'motivations are projected,
懂我说的什么吗?
ye ken what I'm saying?
抱歉 您真的了解戏剧吗?
Sorry, what do you know about drama?
什么 我不了解戏剧 你这个话都说不清楚的货
What don't I know about drama, you,ya jobby-jabber!
没错 虽然我现在看起来是个脏兮兮的流浪汉!
Ah ken maybe no' to look at me, right,but I huvnae always been a dirty Jake!
可是很久之前 我可是我那代最有名的演员之一
See back in the day, I was one of the most famous actors in my generation.
真的吗?
Really?
只要你说得出 我就做得到
You name it, I've done it.
企业宣传片《塔格特》里面的小角色 也给皇家莎士比亚剧团跑过龙套...
Corporate videos, part in Taggart,even done a run at the RSC...
...之后我的演艺事业就一蹶不振 还不如卖驴毛的
..and then the work dried up,worse than a swamp donkey's fud.
闹事 活成这副鬼样子 还得靠行乞才能弄点酒钱
Ah hit the streets, living rough,begging for booze money.
之后就更惨不忍睹了
And then, aye,then things got really bad.
你演过主角吗?
Did you get into heroin?
我演过《圣橡镇少年》
I got into Hollyoaks.
呀 是 赫加蒂夫人啊 晚上好啊
Ah, Mrs Hegarty. Hi. Good evening.
啊!博纳海德(傻瓜)先生真高兴你能来
Ah! Mr Bonehead,so pleased you could make it.
酒吧在哪?我要喝一杯
Where's the bar? I need a drink.
是谁请了他们啊?
Ah, who invited those guys?
我 我觉得你会喜欢
I did. I thought you'd like it.
我知道他们都无家可归 不过他们稍微花点心思 注意下形象也行啊
I get that they're homeless, right,but they could have made a bit of effort.
那边的那个家伙连鞋都没穿
That guy over there's not even got any shoes on.
这就是我提到的
Now this is what I'm talking about.
一个稍微努力下就改头换面的流浪汉
A tramp that's made a little bit of bloody effort.
是啊 虽然你还留着这些破海绵 不过起码你找到了件好衣服!
Yeah, sure you've kept the old clunge sponge, but at least you've found yourself a suit!
你洗得干干净净
You've had a wash.
而且...好像一位领导
And... you're a governor.
哈德赛先生
Mr Hardside.
我现在想起来了...真的非常抱歉 我希望你今晚玩得开心
I've just remembered now...I'm awfully sorry, I hope you have a wonderful evening.
威克斯夫人正在盖特威克机场
Mrs Wickers is at Gatwick.
我们怎么解释她儿子在遭遇了十车连撞事故 又突然活蹦乱跳的呢?
How are we going to explain her son's sudden recovery from a ten-car pileup?
我们有两个选择 一说是圣诞节奇迹 二只能说艾尔非老师残了
Our options are: a) Christmas miracle or two) actually maim Alf.
我比你聪明 老师
No, I'm one step ahead of you, sir.
我爸爸有很多设备啊 以前装颈部扭伤弄赔偿金的时候
Me Dad's got a load of these left over from making whiplash claims.
他当时想攒钱买辆车 太机智了!
He's saving up for a car.Brill-cream!
威克斯先生!快走!
Mr Wickers! Go!
得让大家都到里面去 艾尔非 快 把这个套上
We need to get everyone inside. Alf,quickly, you need to put this on.
为了你的安全着想
Elf 'n' safety!
懂了吗?
Get it?
不过说真的 解说员在全程解说的时候也可能受伤的
But seriously, narrators can get hurt doing all that reading.
啊!
Argh!
愿上帝保佑 祝好运 真主至大
God bless, Mazeltov, Allah Akbar.
狮子王。。。
Arsene Wenger,balls-bis hiya waya!
温馨提示 本校有定点厕所设施
Little bit of housekeeping, this school does have toilet facilities.
我主要是指后面那位先生 我看到你了
That one was mainly aimed at the gentleman at the back.I can see you.
你妹!
Get tae fuck!
圣诞快乐吖 亲
And a very merry Christmas to you,sir.
由威克斯老师为您献上
Over to you, Mr Wickers.
不要太兴奋哦
Drop it like it's hot.
这是圣诞节前夜
It was the night before Christmas
屋子里死气沉沉的 连老鼠都不活跃
and all through the house not a creature was stirring, not even a mouse.
从我身上下来 你个贱人
Oh, get off me, you bell-end!
主角是弗兰克 一个十岁大的男孩
Our hero is Frank,a ten-year-old boy.
你怎么没穿演出服?
Why aren't you wearing your costume?
我不穿紧身裤的 亲
I'm not wearing tights, man.
弗兰克的父母一贫如洗 今天是没什么礼物可得了
Oh! Frank's parents are poor,no presents today,
除非... 听!
unless... hark!
看这是什么?圣诞老人驾着麋鹿 滑着雪橇来了!
What is this? It is Santa with reindeer and sleigh!
驾 驾 驾!
"Ho ho ho!
"我要带给弗兰克圣诞礼物" 圣诞老人如是说
"I'll fetch Frank's presents,"Santa did say,
他捋了捋胡子 从雪橇上下来
as he stroked on his beard and got out of his sleigh.
我在轮椅上呢 蠢货!
I'm in a wheelchair, dickhead!
一头麋鹿去取礼物 圣诞老人还呆在雪橇上
As one of his reindeer went to fetch the present whilst Santa stayed put in his sleigh.
让我出去
Let me out.
我喘不过气来了!天黑了
I can't breathe!Day turned to night.
天又亮了
And then night turned to day.
不知道我有起床气么?
Why did I bother getting out of bed?
弗兰克大声说 声如洪钟
Frank did say, very loudly.
让我出去! - 够了!
Let me out! This is shite!
你说什么?
What did you say?
但是在树下...我不能呼吸了!
But under the tree...I can't breathe!
..这是什么 弗兰克默默地观察着!
..What's this that Frank spies!
是机器小钳子
It's Robocracker.
弗兰克简直不敢相信自己的眼睛!
Frank can't believe his eyes!
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
在那个破箱子里 我快不能呼吸了!
I couldn't breathe in that box!
弗兰克的祈祷 圣诞老人听到了
Frank makes a wish that Santa does hear,
"让这个玩偶活过来
"Make this doll come to life
"我就不躲在自行车棚后面喝啤酒了
"and I'll stop drinking beer behind the bike sheds
"不再欺负弱小
"and being a massive bully
"在学校听老师的话 不惹老师生气
"and constantly going on about how one of his teachers got bummed at boarding school.
顺便提一下 唯一一个 碰过我的屁股的人是我的朋友阿提克斯·霍伊 比如 有次
FYI the only person that's ever touched my bum is my friend Atticus Hoye, like, once,
我们还在伊甸园计划的时候 只有那次
when we were at the Eden Project, this one time.
哎呦!
Gay!
米契尔 这是你自己的表演 你可不能起哄
Mitchell,you can't heckle your own show.
弗兰克和他的朋友有一个梦想 他们要将助人进行到底
Frank and his friend set out on a quest, until they'd helped everyone,they would not rest.
这坨破东西是谁写的?
Who wrote this shite?
我屁股里出来的东西 构思都比这个强
I've seen jobbies come out of my arse with better structure than this.
啊!
Argh!
不要!这是我的个人秀
No! This is my solo.
戴着这么个破头盔 我什么都看不到!老师!
I can't see anything in this stupid helmet! Oi, sir!
米契尔 到这儿来!
Mitchell, come here!
太不专业了 快穿上你的裤子!
It's so unprofessional.Pull your trousers up!
滚开!
Get off!
米契尔 住手!
Mitchell, stop it!
快滚开 你个二货!
Get off. You idiot!
中场休息!
Interval!
同时 在耶路撒冷...
Meanwhile, in Jerusalem...
我要用我的枪占领这块圣地 你个整天撸的货
I called shotgun on the Holy Land,you wanktard.
快滚开吧!耶路撒冷是我的 你个眼瞎的!
Oh, do one!Jerusalem is mine, you Jap's eye!
我要把你弄起来 放到茶叶袋里扔了
I'm going to pin you down and teabag ya.
得了吧 把轮子放这儿来
Come on, get the cogs in here.
剧本里根本没有
Not even in the script.
但是机器人小钳子来了
But here comes Robocracker.
他想到了一个让两方都不吃亏的办法 一城两治
He has an idea of a neutral shared city in a two-state solution,
他将通过舞蹈来表达自己的主意
which he will explain through the medium of expressive dance.
就是这样
That's right.
现在是和谐之舞!
It's now time for the Tolerance Dance!
没错小钳子让大家一团和气
Yeah, Robocracker brings everyone together.
奇迹啊奇迹!
It's a miracle!
疼啊 弄我眼里去了
Ah, it's in my bloody eye.
简直就是奇迹!
It's a miracle!
本是心疼迷失的结局
They've put an end to heartache and loss,
现在我们的勇士必须要解决祸首了
but now our brave pair must take on the boss.
我会抓到你的 机器小钳子!
I'll get you, Robocracker!
你别做梦了 我可是个正常的人类男孩!
No, you shan't for I am a real boy!
我的罗密欧在哪?
Where is my Romeo?
我知道了 一定是毒药结果了他的生命
Poison, I see,hath been his timeless end.
我要吻着你的嘴唇...
I will kiss thy lips...
也许这上面还留着一些毒液
happily some poison yet doth hang on them.
你的嘴唇还是温暖的
Thy lips are warm.
让我死了吧!
Let me die!
唉 毫无希望 没有办法
Alas there's no hope, no treatment,
无药可救 小钳子的生命就这样消逝了 弗兰克向他告别 深情相...
no drug, as Robo's life fades away,Frank bids adieu with a hu...
相拥!
Hug!
剧本里写的是拥抱
In the script it says hug.
看发生了什么?
But what's this?
小钳子重获新生 最终化身成为了一个真正的男孩!
Robocracker has been reincarnated and finally he's a real boy!
大结局!
The end!
你们真棒 从这边出去
Come on, you lot. Out you get.
你们还不去休息室吗?
Haven't you got homes to go to?
演得真好
Well done.
谬赞了
Oh, thank you.
凭良心说
Fair do's.
你的讲述很感人
Your narrative arc was engaging,
但真正深入人心的 是观众对
but the pleasurable representations dinnae depend on the likeness of the thing
他们所塑造形象的喜爱度 你懂我的意思么 蠢货?
that they are portraying. You know what I mean, ya minging bag o' shite?
谨遵教诲 下次我会注意的
Oh, I'll bear that in mind for next time.
我勇敢的小宝贝啊!
My brave little baby!
妈妈
Mummy.
你能来我真是太意外了
I can't believe you came.
一听说你出事 我们就赶来了
We came as soon as we heard about the accident.
出事?是我...
The accident? Me...
..忘记邀请她 那个意外!
..forgetting to put her invite in the fricking post, that accident!
你邀请了我妈?好吧 其实是米契尔阁下的主意
You invited my mum? Well, it was Mr Mitchell's idea.
不要太感谢我 迪克斯
Don't go soppy on me, Dickers.
你哈维尔叔叔也在这儿!
And Uncle Javier is here too!
真棒 哈维尔叔叔啊
Great, Uncle Javier.
我一直挺想他的
I've really missed him.
我的小男子汉
Oh, me valiente hombre.
艾尔非 哈维尔叔叔真为你骄傲
Alfie,Uncle Javier is so proud of you.
我们一定会查出 谁把你害得这么惨 我们一定会追究到底
We're going to find the men who put you in this chair, and we're going to make them pay.
有人能阻止费兰度·托利斯欺负我么?
Can someone stop Fernando Torres trying' to bum me?
哈维尔 那不是艾尔非
Javier, that's not Alfie.
这个才是...您好
This is... Hi.
你好啊
Hey.
我就知道是你
I knew it.
刚刚是小玩笑而已
It was a little joke.
妈妈 哈维尔叔叔 这就是我跟你们提过的女孩
Er, Mum, Javier, this is the girl I've been telling you about.
罗西
Rosie.
见到您很荣幸
It's so nice to meet you.
所以你会留下来过圣诞节吗?
So will you be staying for Christmas?
在我的艾尔非小宝贝儿身体好转之前 我们会一直呆在这儿
We are going to stay until little Alfie is better.
我们最好赶快去艾尔非的教室 有圣诞大餐喔!
We better head to Alfie's classroom for Christmas dinner!
谁要吃烤鸡!
Who wants turkey!
你有没有收到西汉姆联队的门票?
So did you get the West Ham ticket?
那个是你给我的?
Oh, you got me that?
那你想去么?
So do you want to go?
当然了
All right, yeah.
我的意思是 那代表不了什么 比如 算了...
I mean, it don't mean nothing or, like, whatever...
你现在就别想那场表演了 亲爱的
You can give up that act now, babes.
猜猜我对那些做了什么?什么?
Guess what I done with them crackers?What?
互相交换
Swapped the jokes.
有个问题要问您
Here's one for you.
百分之九十的人都喜欢什么?
What do nine out of ten people enjoy?
群...
Gang ra...
喔哦
Rawr!
就像一头狮子
An impression of a lion.
抱歉 女士们 先生们
Excuse me, ladies and gents.
我要到走廊里一下 借用一下你们的厕所
Er, just going to go down the hallway to only use your lavatory.
谢谢
Er, so, thank youse.
哈 博纳海德的生活终于步入正轨了
Aw, Bonehead's got his life back on track.
你的剧真的帮了他呢
Your play really helped him.
我只是觉得 我们给他看了大点的那个照片 真的很棒
I just think it's great that we've been able to show him the bigger picture. Mmm.
对了 我给你准备了 一个小礼物
Oh, I got you a tiny silly little present thing.
米契尔 那头驴没一起来么?
Mitchell,how's that donkey coming along?
一个小时前 它就从罗马尼亚来了
It arrived from Romania about an hour ago.
太好了
Oh, amazing.
你拿到证书了吗?什么证书?
Have you got the certificate? What certificate?
好吧 这里有只半驴
Right, here's half the donkey.
另一半我交给厨房了
The rest I gave to the kitchens.
我觉得你自己吃不上
I figured you couldn't eat it all.
艾尔非雷德 这肉真好吃 嫩滑多汁啊
Alfredo, this meat is lovely!It's so bloody moist!
布 布勃莱!
B-Buble!
也就是说 我们可以天天听这个CD 一直到圣诞节喽?
Does this mean we can listen to it every day until Christmas?
我真的真的爱死你了
I guess I must really love you.
老师硬了!
Sir's got a boner!